A Guide to the Nancy Bondurant Jones Papers, 1909-2011 (bulk 1991-2007): SC 0192
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Nancy Bondurant Jones Papers,
1909-2011 (bulk 1991-2007)
Special Collections, James Madison University
Jones, Nancy Bondurant, 1930-2017
SC 0192
6.53 cubic feet; 19 boxes
The Nancy Bondurant Jones Papers, 1909-2011 (bulk 1991-2007), document the career and personal life of local teacher and writer Nancy Bondurant Jones. The collection mainly consists of research subject files, newspapers and clippings, correspondence, ephemera, speeches, and business and organizational documents. Also included are responses and letters from JMU alumni and Presidents Burruss, Duke, and Miller that Jones acquired during her research for Rooted on Bluestone Hill.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
A small portion of the collection related to her work on Rooted on Bluestone Hill was donated by Nancy Bondurant Jones in 2004. The bulk of the collection was donated by Martin Jones and Randy Jones, Nancy's sons, in May 2017.
Other Formats Available
All media items are pending processing and reformatting. Media items include floppy disks containing Jones's articles and other written documents as well as cassette and microcassette tapes that mainly appear to be interviews that Jones conducted with Dr. Ronald E. Carrier, Lucille Smead, Harry Caplinger, and others.
Appraisal Information
Due to duplication in the Daily News-Record and other periodicals, a collection of scrapbooks containing exclusively newspaper clippings of Jones's articles was returned to the donors.
Bio/Historical Note
Nancy Bondurant Jones (1930-2017) was a well-known writer and historian in the Shenandoah Valley. She was born to Dr. Charles H. and Therma Barclay Bondurant in Roanoke. In 1956, she married Phillip Lawrence Jones, who passed away in 1979. She had two daughters, three sons, six grandchildren, and two great-grandchildren at the time of her death in December 2017.
Jones began her extensive teaching and writing career by getting her Bachelor of Arts at Shepherd College in West Virginia in 1953. Beyond Shepherd, she did additional work at George Washington University, University of Maryland, James Madison University, and University of Virginia. She also received fellowships from the University of Virginia and American University.
After twenty-nine years of teaching at schools in Montgomery County, Maryland and in Rockingham County at Elkton and Turner Ashby high schools, Jones spent the reminder of her career as a freelance writer. Her writing extended across newspapers, journals, speeches, and published books. Some of her most notable writing was done for the local newspaper, the Daily News-Record in which she wrote a weekly column, "Remembrances," for eleven years based on personal memories supported with historical fact. After completing her writing for the DNR, she went on to contribute columns and articles to the Staunton-based paper eightyone, and to JMU's Montpelier magazine. Jones also penned over a dozen books for various local businesses and organizations. Some notable titles include: Rooted on Bluestone Hill: A History of James Madison University (2004), Called to Care: A History of the Nursing Program at Rockingham Memorial Hospital (2004), and Ageless Legacy: A History of Virginia Mennonite Retirement Community (2004), all of which were nominated for the Library of Virginia's outstanding non-fiction award.
Outside of her writing career, Jones was active in the local and statewide community. In 1983, she ran unsuccessfully as the Democratic candidate for the Virginia House of Delegates District 27. She was also the former president of the Harrisonburg Pilot Club, the Rockingham Country Teacher's Association, and the Shenandoah Branch of the National Association of American Pen Women. Beyond these organizations, Jones served on the boards of Greater Madison at JMU, the Sorenson Institute, and the Arts Council of the Valley. Personally, she was a member of the Emmanuel Episcopal Church and opened one of the first bed and breakfasts in the area in the mid-1980s.
For her extensive work through teaching, writing, and community involvement Jones was given a few honors including being cited in the 1989/1990 edition of Who's Who in American Education and being named Women of the Year in 2000 by the Working Women's Forum.
In addition to all this work, Jones also worked at JMU for eight years. After retiring from teaching English at Turner Ashby High School in 1989, Jones began working for JMU in former President Dr. Ronald E. Carrier's office as the social events coordinator for Carrier and his wife, Edith. Soon she began writing Dr. Carrier's speeches and other documents as requested.In the early 1990s, Dr. Carrier commissioned her to write a book on the history of JMU that would appeal to a general audience. This book, Rooted on Bluestone Hill, was published in 2004.
Scope and Content
The Nancy Bondurant Jones Papers, 1909-2011 (bulk 1991-2007), consist of 19 boxes and 6.53 cubic feet of materials primarily consisting of research subject files, newspapers and clippings, correspondence, ephemera, speeches, and business and organizational documents. The bulk of the papers correspond to Shenandoah Valley and Virginia history, although some of the papers relate to national history including historical events like the Los Angeles Riots and women's suffrage. Other topics, like cancer or cars, are broader in scope. The collection also includes responses, forms, and letters from JMU alumni, faculty emeriti, and former university presidents that Jones acquired during her research for Rooted on Bluestone Hill. Arranged in two series, there is overlap in some instances between the two. The original, intended arrangement from the creator has been maintained where possible. Changes to the arrangement include alphabetizing where needed, slight changes to folder titles when necessary, and interfiling loose papers with existing files.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
1: Subject Files, 1909-2010
2: Personal Papers, 1979-2011
Series 1: Subject Files is arranged alphabetically. Series 2: Personal Papers is arranged chronologically and then alphabetically.
Separated Material
All published monographs have been cataloged individually and placed in Special Collections' rare book collection.
Bibliography
Obituary for Nancy Bondurant Jones, Daily News-Record, December 14, 2017.
Jones, Nancy B. Rooted on Blue Stone Hill: A History of James Madison University. Santa Fe, NM; Staunton, VA: Center for American Places, 2004.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Marable, Eleanor Beatrice, 1893-1982; Burruss, Julian Ashby, 1876-1947; Gifford, Walter J; Keezell, George Bernard, 1854-1931; Carrier, Ronald E; Carrier, Michael L; McNallie, Robyn M; Whitman, Richard F; State Normal and Industrial School for Women (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- History; State Normal School for Women at Harrisonburg (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- History; Madison College -- History; James Madison University -- History; Education, Higher -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg -- History; College students -- Manners and customs; Curriculum change -- History -- 20th century; Teachers colleges -- History; Universities and colleges -- Virginia -- History
Genre and Form Terms:
Printed Ephemera; Letters (correspondence); Articles; Research (documents); Drafts (documents); Speeches (Documents); Photographs
- Series 1: Subject Files, 1909-2010 (bulk 1991-2005)
  Scope and Content
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Series 1: Subject Files, 1909-2010 (bulk 1991-2005), contains papers relating to research that Jones did for her professional writing. It also comprises of papers related to JMU's history, including papers from the 2004 collection, general JMU history, and files related to Dr. Carrier. The series also includes documents and ephemera from the Harrisonburg community, including the local government and local events. The topics of the files range from local to national interest.
  Combined from the 2004 portion of the collection relating to Jones's research for Rooted on Bluestone Hill, the series includes responses to forms Jones sent to faculty emeriti and graduates soliciting personal experiences and memories for the book, plus a few older items that respondents sent her. These include several letters by Dr. Julian Burruss, the first president of the university, to Beatrice Marable, the first student applicant at the new school in 1909, and the text of a speech Ms. Marable gave in 1945. Items from Presidents Duke and Miller are also included in the 2004 portion of the collection. Interviews concerning the conflicts between Dr. Carrier and faculty over the curriculum in the 1990s, a short memoir by Dr. Carrier, and an interview with Dr. Carrier's son, Michael are incorporated into the collection as well.
  - 1864: The Valley Aflame Newspaper, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1927, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1950s, 1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1960s-1970s, 1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1990s Overview Decade, 1990, 1994, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1992 + First Night, 1992-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1993-94, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1997, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - A David, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - AAUW [American Association of University Women], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ABC + Moonshine, 1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Adoption Search, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ads, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - AIDS, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Airships, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Alzheimer's, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - American Dream Unraveled, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arboretum, 1988, 1990, 1993, 1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Architecture, 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Architecture, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Art/Artists, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Aunt Era, 1993, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Automobiles, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - B. Marable, 1909-1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Baseball - Rockingham County Baseball League, 1984-1987,1990, 1996, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bed and Breakfast Articles, 1992, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bennett, Elizabeth & Jesse, 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Berry, Dave, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bible Women, 1991, 1999, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bingham, Caleb George, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Black Americans, 2009, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - To Black Freedom by W.M Good, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Blacksmiths - Fred Fisher, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Blizzard '96 & Others, 1996, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Boating - Shenandoah & James River, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Boyd, Belle, 1991, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Boys Band - Harrisonburg, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bradley Foundry, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Brass Bands - Timberville & Others, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Bridgewater, 1992 - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Nellie, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Brunk, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Byrd, John, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cancer, 1991, 1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Carpenter Family, 1993, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Dr. Ronald E. Carrier, 1997-2000, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Carrier Speeches, 2006, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Cars, 1991, 1994, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Caves, 1998, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Center for American Places, 2001, 2002, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Chamber of Commerce/ Convention & Visitors Bureau, 1993-1995, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Charles Wynes, 1980, 2006-2007, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chestnut, 1991, 1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Children's Home and Orphanages, 1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Christ the King, 2005, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Christmas Letters & Menus, 1991, 1992, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Churches, 1990, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Civil War, 1991, 1995-1997, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Clark, Henry, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Clubs, 1997, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Colonial Life (Punishment), undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Columns - DNR, 1990, 1991, 1998, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Comics - Hobbs, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Contests, 1994, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Copyright Info, 2001, 2002, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Country Stores, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Crossroads - EMU, 1994, 1995, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Culebra/Puerto Rica, 1994, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Daily News Leader: 1900s A Century of Change, 1999, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Daily News Record Newspaper, 1921, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Daily News Record: 20th Century Look Back, 1999, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Dam - Rawley, 1993, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dating, 1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dayton, 1990, 1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dayton - Civil War, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Dayton Learning Center, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - D.C. National Guard - MISC History - Mike Berger, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - D-Day, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Death with Dignity, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Desert Storm Operation - War (following Operation Desert Shield), 1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Disasters, 1996, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Dogs, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Donning Company, 1990, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Doris Dean, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Dry River/ Gum Run, 1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Earhart and Female Pilots, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Easter, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Eastern Mennonite School & College, 1992, 1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Eaton Vance Financial, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Edison, Thomas Alva, 1993, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Education - Hist., undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Education - Today, 1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Eightyone Newspapers, 2001, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Elkton, 1988, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Email Chains, 2000, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Emory, Bertha, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - English, Commentaries On, 1980, 1986-1987, 1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Episcopal Church & Bishop Madison, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - ERA, 1978, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Faculty Emeritus, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Farming/ Kemper Jarrels, 1991, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Farrell, Richard, 1989, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Fires, 1990, 1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - First Ladies of VA/ The Constitution, 2006, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Fishing, 1994, 1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Flogging & Other Legal Punishment, 1994, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Floods, 1990-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Floral Arrangements, 2001 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Folklore - Shenandoah Valley, 1992, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Following Directions + "Friday Afternoons", 1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Football, 2006, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Fort Laramie Scout, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Fredrickson, Edna/ Otto, 1993, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Gatewood/ Geronimo, 1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Genman, G.E, 1992, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Gibbons, Josephine, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Girl Scouts, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Graduates, 1993-1997, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Graduates - Memoirs, 1916, 1923-1924, 1975, 1993-1996, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Grant Info, 1991-1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Grottos, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Halloween + Ghost Tales, 1988, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Harrison, Daniel, 1994, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Harrisonburg Downtown, 1982-2002, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Harrisonburg-Rockingham Community Services Guide, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Harrisonburg-Rockingham Historical Society, 1992, 1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Harrisonburg-Rockingham Newsletters, 2004-2010 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Hartman, 1994, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Health Care, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Herblock + Hobbs Comic, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Historic Homes, 1992, 1993, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Historical Society: '89, '90, '91, 1990-1996, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Hoboes, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Hoboes, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Holidays, 1983, 1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Hosteller Drug Store, 2009, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hotel Roanoke & Jefferson, 1992, 1994, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hughes/ Williamson Pharmacy, 1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hunting, 1992-1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hymns, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Indians, 1993, 1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Jackson River Case, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The Jefferson Hotel, 1995, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - JMU, 2004, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - JMU Basketball, 1996, 1997, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - JMU Extras - use 2nd printing, 1931, 1998, 2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - JMU-Related Columns, 1994-1996, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Jones, General + Malinda Rice + Others, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Jones, N.B. Miscellaneous, 1917, 1943, 1952-1957 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Jones Williams Gabriel, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Keezletown/McGaheysville, 1992, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Kelly, Brain C. Best Little Stories, 1995, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Kennedy Newspaper, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Knitting, 1995, 2002, 2005-2008, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Lackawanna/ Riverton, 2002, 2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - L.A. Riots 1992, 1965, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Law Enforcement/ Police Sheriffs, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Lee, Robert E. - Mother, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Lincolns, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Lindbergh, 2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Local History - MISC, 1973, 1996-2001, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lottery, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Madison, Bishop James, 2007, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Magazines/ NAACP, 1977, 1998, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Malls, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Mark Warner, etc, 2001, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Mary Draper Ingles + Hochstetler Massacres, 1990, 1996, 1997, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Matthew Fontaine Maury, 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - McDaniel Brothers - Shenandoah Valley Drywall, 1994, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - McGaheysville/ Keezeltown, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - MCV - Sanger, William T., 1996 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Medal of Honor, 1982, 1990, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Memorials, 1993, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Mennonites, 2005, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Merck, 1990, 1991, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Mercy House, 1991, 1993, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Mills & Agriculture, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - MISC, 1990-1992, 1996, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - MISC - Local History, 2008, 2009, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - MISC - need to keep + medical growth + changes to book, 1996, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Monticello, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Monticello/ Michie Tavern/ Montpelier, 1993, 1999, 2005, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Mosby, 1986, 1994, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Mount Clinton School, 1956, 1991, 1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Mount Crawford, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - NAACP, 2006 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - NAACP, 2008 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Names, 1991, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Names of Local Interest, 1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Naylor, Phyllis, 1993-1995, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - NetMusic Works (Rain), 2008 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Newspapers, 1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - New York, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Nielson Construct[ion], 2001, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Obaugh, Wallace, 1990, undated (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Olympics, undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Oxfam, 1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Pakyar Interview Notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Paul, Jane, 1975, 1991-1993, 1997, undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Peaks of Otter, undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - People: MISC, 1989-1991, undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Pershing, General John S., undated (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Peter Heneberger - DNR Column 509 - June 5, 2001, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Photographs & Images - JMU Historic, 1909-1945, 1970-1996, undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Photos, 1943, undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Political Photos, undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - P.O. + MISC, 1985, 1988, 1990, 1991, undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Possible Columns 1, 1991-1996, 2006-2009, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Possible Columns 2, 1991-1996, 2006-2009, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - P.O.W.'s, 1987, 1993, 2008, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Presidents, 1993-1998, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Quota Club, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Quotes, 2002, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Radio/ TV WSVA, 1995-1996, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Radio Workshop Presentation, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Railroads, 1916, 1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Reed, Walter, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Restaurants - Friddle's, 1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Rice, John, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - RMH MISC, 1973, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Roads - Valley (Turnpikes), 1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Rockingham Construction, 1985, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Rockingham County, 1997, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Rockingham Country Correspondence, 1995, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Rockingham County - Early Settlers (German) + Penn., 1993, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Romance & Crime, 1998, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Rotary, 1971, 1993-1996, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Sally Tompkins, 1986, 1987, 1990-1991, 2006, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Salvation Army, 1980-1982, 1987-1991, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Schools, 1956, 1990-1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Service Clubs - Exchange, Rotary, Kiwanis, 1996, 1997, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Seven Wonders of Ancient World, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Sharing &Seminarian - Mennonite Mutual Aid & Eastern Mennonite University, 1993-1995, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Shenandoah Bicentennial, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Shenandoah Valley Business Journal, 1994, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Shenandoah Valley Electric Coop., 2004-2005, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Shenandoah Valley Highways, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Shenandoah Women, 1998, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Sherman, Elizabeth, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Showalter, Galen - Notes, 1991, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Showker, Zane, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Singers/ Dancers, Writers, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Singers Glen, 1994, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Sipe, George E.: Civil War, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Smith, Colonel Abraham, 1722-1783, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Smith House, 2005, undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - State Parks, 2006, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Staunton - MISC, 2001, 2002, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Staunton + Wilson, 2004, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Stuart, Sally (ECW), undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Suffrage (19th Amendment), 1995, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Superstitions, 1988-1989, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Suter's Handcrafted Furniture, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Swartzendruber, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Teaching, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Theaters, 1991-1995, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Tide Springs, 2009, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Toll Roads, 1991, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Trains, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Turkey Festival, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - "Tweetsie" - Narrow Gauge Railroad Rockingham County, 1996, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)